Robert S. Phillips Papers
Robert S. Phillips Papers
1964-1989
Phillips, Robert, 1938-
33 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, author, editor of the Letters of Delmore Schwartz. Collection includes correspondence, manuscripts, and published material. Writings comprise a large assortment of manuscripts and production records for Phillips' books, as well as holograph and typescript manuscripts for essays, poems, reviews, stories, and interviews with William Goyen, Philip Larkin, Joyce Carol Oates, Karl Shapiro, Elizabeth Spencer, and Marya Zaturenska.
144593
Biographical History
Robert S. Phillips (1938- ) is an American poet, author, and editor, with more than 30 volumes of poetry, fiction, criticism, and belles lettres to his name.
Born in 1938 in Milford, Delaware, Phillips graduated from Syracuse University's creative writing program. He is currently (May 2007) a professor of English at the University of Houston; he was also director of the Creative Writing Program there from 1991 to 1996. His honors include a 1996 Enron Teaching Excellence Award, a Pushcart Prize, an American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters Award in Literature, a New York State Council on the Arts CAPS Grant in Poetry, MacDowell Colony and Yaddo Fellowships, a National Public Radio Syndicated Fiction Project Award, a Syracuse University Arents Pioneer Medal, and Texas Institute of Letters membership. In 1998 he was named a John and Rebecca Moore Scholar at the University of Houston.
[Portions of biographical sketch taken from Mr. Phillips' faculty home page at the University of Houston, http://www.uh.edu/cwp/faculty/phillips.htm, retrieved 11 May 2007.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert S. Phillips Papers contains correspondence, writings and memorabilia. Correspondence contains that of both individuals and organizations, and includes poets (John Ashbery, Mitchell Cullin, Sybil Pittman Estess, William Heyen, Denise Levertov, Delmore Schwartz, Elizabeth Spencer, Daniel Stern), writers (Edward Albee, Donald Barthelme, Saul Bellow, Harold Bloom, Paul Bowles, William S. Burroughs, Raymond Carver, Jules Feiffer, Horace Gregory, Granville Hicks, Shirely Jackson, Erica Jong, Norman Mailer, Joyce Carol Oates, Marya Zaturenska), artists (Paul Cadmus), publishers (E.P. Dutton, Farrar Straus & Giroux, David R. Godine, Harper Collins, Johns Hopkins University Press, Gibbs Smith, University of Houston Press), literary magazines (Chelsea, Commonweal, Dark Horse Literary Review, Hudson Review, Manhattan Poetry Review, Ontario Review, Paris Review, Shenandoah) and professional societies and organizations (Gulf Coast Association of Creative Writing Teachers, National Endowment for the Arts, Poetry Society of America, Yaddo).
Writings comprises typescripts, production records, and other material relating to Phillips' writing -- books, essays, interviews, novels, poetry, reviews, scripts, speeches, and short stories. At the end is a small section of miscellaneous material which includes audio and video cassettes with interviews and readings, biographical sketches of authors, and assorted other writings.
Memorabilia contains printed material -- there are a few programs and announcements but the bulk consists of issues of various periodicals in which Phillip's work appears.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is alphabetized by name of correspondent. Writings are subdivided by type (books, essays, interviews, novels, poetry, reviews, scripts, speeches, and short stories) and within that arranged alphabetically by title. Memorabilia periodicals are arranged alphabetically by title of publication.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Goyen, William.; Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982.; Heyen, William, 1940-; Jong, Erica.; Larkin, Philip.; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997.; Mazzaro, Jerome.; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938-; Philbrick, Stephen.; Phillips, Robert, 1938-; Poulin, A., Jr., 1938-1996.; Schwartz, Delmore, 1913-1966.; Shapiro, Karl, 1913-2000.; Spencer, Elizabeth, 1921-; Zaturenska, Marya, 1902-1982.; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Critics -- United States.; Novelists, American.; Poets, American.; Correspondence.; Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Critics.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The following material is completely restricted: Erica Jong, Joyce Carol Oates, Elizabeth Spencer.
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Aaron, Jonathan (Box 1)
  - Abse, Dannie (Box 1)
  - Academy of American Poets (Box 1)
  - Ackart, Robert C. (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Diane (Box 1)
  - Adams, Alice (Box 1)
  - Adams, Barbara Block (Box 1)
  - Adcock, Betty (Box 1)
  - Albee, Edward (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Michael (Box 1)
  - Allen, Dick (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters (Box 1)
  - American Center for Artists, See White, James
  - Andrews, Duncan (Box 1)
  - Aplon, Roger (Box 1)
  - Appleman, Philip
    - "Apes and Angels", ms. (Box 1)
  - Archibald, Andrew (Box 1)
  - Ashbery, John
    - "Can You Hear, Bird" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 1)
  - Ashmore, Helen (Box 1)
  - Atlas, James (Box 1)
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton (Box 1)
  - Auden, Wystan Hugh (Box 1)
  - Axinn, Donald E. (Box 1)
  - Bachardy, Don (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Ellen (Mrs. Ernst) (Box 1)
  - Baker, Dorothy Zayatz (Box 1)
  - Baker, Thomas Warren
    - "Paperwhite Narcissus", ms. (Box 1)
    - "Robert Phillips: a Supplementary Checklist", 1981-1991; ms. (Box 1)
  - Bakken, Christopher (Box 1)
  - Balakian, Anna (Box 1)
  - Balakian, Peter (Box 1)
  - Barber, David
    - "The Spirit Level" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 1)
  - Barney, William D. (Box 1)
  - Barresi, Dorothy
    - "The Post-Rapture Diner" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 1)
  - Barrett, William (Box 1)
  - Barson, Frederick (Box 1)
  - Barthelme, Donald (Box 1)
  - Baskin, Leonard (Box 1)
  - Bass, Rick (Box 1)
  - Bawer, Bruce
    - "Coast to Coast", page proofs (Box 1)
    - "The Middle Generation", ms. (Box 1)
  - Bawer, Theodore Bruce, See Bawer, Bruce
  - Beattie, Ann (Box 1A)
  - Bedell, Jack B.
    - "What Passes for Love", production records (Box 1A)
  - Bedford Books (Box 1A)
  - Bell, Madison Smartt (Box 1A)
  - Bellow, Saul (Box 1A)
  - Benedikt, Michael (Box 1A)
  - Benitez, Armando
    - "Rhyme of the Fall of Berlin" / by Henry Firebaugh, ms. (Box 1A)
  - Berger, Arthur (Box 1A)
  - Bernard, Artis (Box 1A)
  - Berns, Walter (Box 1A)
  - Berryhill, Michael (Box 1A)
  - Bingham, Sallie (Box 1A)
  - Birstein, Ann
    - "Apple Pie and Coffee", ms. (Box 1A)
  - Bissell, Trim
    - "Getting There", ms. (Box 1A)
  - Blake, Glenn
    - "How Far From the Water?", ms. (Box 1A)
  - Bloom, Amy (Box 1A)
  - Bloom, Harold (Box 1A)
  - BOA Editions Ltd. (Box 1A)
  - Boll, Heinrich (Box 1A)
  - Bond, Bruce (Box 1A)
  - Bonnard, Robert Andrew
    - "At Auden's Tomb and Other Sights", ms. (Box 1A)
    - "The Jassack He Is William Carlos Williams, ms. (Box 1A)
  - Booth, Martin (Box 1A)
  - Booth, Philip E. (Box 1A)
  - Boulevard (Box 1A)
  - Bowles, Paul (Box 1A)
  - Bowman, Sylvia E., See Twayne Publishers, Inc.
  - Boyle, Kay (Box 1A)
  - Branch, Edgar Marquess (Box 1A)
  - Braybrooke, Neville (Box 1A)
  - Brazos Bookstore (Box 1A)
  - Bricuth, John, See Irwin, John T.
  - Brind, Stephen and Diana
    - "The Havana Clipper", ms. (Box 1A)
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm (Box 1A)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (Box 1A)
  - Brock-Broido, Lucie
    - "The Master Letters" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 1A)
  - Brogger, Erik
    - "A Normal Life", ms. (Box 1A)
  - Brown, Eric L. (Box 1A)
  - Brown, Rosellen (Box 1A)
  - Bruchac, Joseph (Box 1A)
  - Bryan, Sharon (Box 1A)
  - Bryant, Deyonne (Box 1A)
  - Brynteson, Susan (Box 1A)
  - Buckman, Gertrude (Mrs. Delmore Schwartz) (Box 1A)
  - Bucknell, Katherine (Box 1A)
  - Buechner, Frederick (Box 1A)
  - Burgin, Richard, See Boulevard
  - Burnshaw, Stanley (Box 1A)
  - Burroughs, William S. (Box 1A)
  - Burton, Philip Ward (Box 1A)
  - Busa, Christopher (Box 1A)
  - Busby, Mark (Box 1A)
  - Busch, Frederick (Box 1A)
  - Butscher, Edward (Box 1A)
  - Cadmus, Paul (Box 2)
  - Calisher, Hortense (Box 2)
  - Cambor, Kathleen (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Joseph (Box 2)
  - CAPS (Box 2)
  - Caram, Eve La Salle (Box 2)
  - Carlile, D. J. (Box 2)
  - Carr, Virginia Spencer (Box 2)
  - Carrier, Constance (Box 2)
  - Carroll & Graf Publishers (Box 2)
  - Carruth, Hayden (Box 2)
  - Carter, James Earl (Box 2)
  - Carter, Robert A. (Box 2)
  - Cartwright, Jon
    - "The Mirror", ms. (Box 2)
  - Carver, Raymond (Box 2)
  - Carver, Wayne (Box 2)
  - Cassells, Cyrus (Box 2)
  - Chaney, Dolph L.
    - "Project Z", ms. (Box 2)
  - Chappell, Fred
    - "Spring Garden" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 2)
  - Chartier, David
    - "Burning Valleys", ms. (Box 2)
  - Chelsea, See also Foerster, Richard (Box 2)
  - Cheuse, Alan (Box 2)
  - Chewning, Emily Blair
    - "Good Faith", ms. (Box 2)
    - "Heart Roots", ms. (Box 2)
  - Christopher, Nicholas (Box 2)
  - Ciardi, John (Box 2)
  - Civetta, Michele, See Schwartz, Delmore: "In Dreams Begin Responsibilities" (film)
  - Clampitt, Amy (Box 2)
  - Clark, Eleanor (Box 2)
  - Clemente, Vince (Box 2)
  - Cobb, William
    - "Blue Souvenirs", ms. (Box 2)
  - Cole, Henri, See Academy of American Poets
  - Cole, William (Box 2)
  - Collins, Billy
    - "The Art of Drowning", ms. (Box 2)
  - Columbia University Libraries (Box 2)
  - Commonweal (Box 2)
  - Confrontation, See Tucker, Martin
  - Conlon, Christopher
    - "'Fox-Teeth in Your Heart': Inscriptions of Sexuality in the Poetry of Tennessee Williams", ms. (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Review, See also Shipley, Vivian (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Authors (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Literary Criticism (Box 2)
  - Contoski, Victor (Box 2)
  - Cooley, John R. (Box 2)
  - Copland, Aaron (Box 2)
  - Corsaro, Frank (Box 2)
  - Cortez, Sarah
    - "How To Undress a Cop", ms. (Box 2)
  - Corva, Dominic (Box 2)
  - Costanzo, Gerald (Box 2)
  - Coursen, Herbert R. (Box 2)
  - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 2)
  - Craven, Jerry
    - "Artist at the Jungle's Edge" (Chapter 1), ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Shooting a Monkey", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Snake Mountain", ms. (Box 2A)
  - Creative Artists Public Service Program, See CAPS
  - Creeley, Robert (Box 2A)
  - Cremins, Melanie Danburg, See Danburg, Melanie A.
  - Cremins, Robert (Box 2A)
  - Crossley-Holland, Kevin (Box 2A)
  - Crouch, Robin N.
    - "Primitivism and Urbanity: T. S. Eliot", ms. (Box 2A)
  - Cubbage, Elinor P.
    - "Interview with Robert Francis", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Robert Francis: a Critical Biography", ms. (Box 2A)
  - Cullin, Mitchell
    - "Afternoon Misdemeanors", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Branches", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "The House of Special Purpose", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "6 Poems", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Tideland" (excerpt), ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Totem", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "Wormwood", ms. (Box 2A)
  - Danburg, Melanie A.
    - "Addictionary", ms. (Box 2A)
    - "The Right Star", ms. (Box 2A)
  - Daniels, Sally (Box 2A)
  - Dark Horse Literary Review (Box 2A)
  - Davis, Hope (Box 2A)
  - Davis, Robert Gorham (Box 2A)
  - Davis, William Virgil (Box 2A)
  - Dawkins, Cecil (Box 2A)
  - Delta Upsilon Fraternity (Box 2A)
  - Deming, Richard (Box 2A)
  - DeMott, Benjamin (Box 2A)
  - DePietro, Thomas (Box 2A)
  - Desaulneiers, Janet (Box 2A)
  - Diamond, David (Box 2A)
  - Diaz, Tony
    - "Jester's Apprentice", ms. (fragment) (Box 2A)
    - "Jester's Apprentice", ms. (Box 2A)
  - Dickey, James (Box 2A)
  - Dickson, Rose (Box 2A)
  - Dickstein, Morris (Box 2A)
  - Dictionary of American Biography (Box 2A)
  - Dictionary of Literary Biography (Box 2A)
  - Digges, Deborah
    - "Rough Music" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 2A)
  - Dikaia Foundation, Inc., See Delta Upsilon Fraternity
  - Dike, Donald A. (Box 2A)
  - Dike, Sally Daniels, See Daniels, Sally
  - Di Piero, W. S.
    - "Shadows Burning" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 2A)
  - Djerassi, Carl (Box 2A)
  - Doolittle, Hilda, See H. D.
  - Doubleday (Box 2A)
  - Dulany, Harris (Box 2A)
  - Duncan, Erika (Box 2A)
  - Duncan, Robert (Box 2A)
  - Dunn, Stephen (Box 2A)
  - Dupee, Barbara (Mrs. Frederick) (Box 2A)
  - [E. P.] Dutton, Inc. (Box 2A)
  - Eaton, Charles Edward (Box 2A)
  - Eberhart, Richard (Box 2A)
  - Eberts, Max (Box 2A)
  - Economou, George (Box 2A)
  - Edel, Leon (Box 2A)
  - Eliot, Valerie (Mrs. T. S.) (Box 2A)
  - Elledge, Jim (Box 2A)
  - Ellis, Elinor S. (Box 2A)
  - Enright, Dennis Joseph (Box 2A)
  - Epstein, Daniel Mark (Box 2A)
  - Erlanger, David Michael (Box 2A)
  - [Willard R.] Espy Literary Foundation (Box 2A)
  - Estess, Sybil Pittman
    - "Almost Nothing One Way", poetry collection ms. (Box 2A)
  - Eyle, Alexandra (Box 2A)
  - Fagles, Robert (Box 3)
  - Fairchild, B. H. (Box 3)
  - Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Farrell, James Thomas (Box 3)
  - Federman, Raymond (Box 3)
  - Feiffer, Jules (Box 3)
  - Feirstein, Frederick
    - "The End of the Twentieth Century", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Family History", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Melting the Glacier", ms. (Box 3)
    - "The Psychiatrist at the Cocktail Party", ms. (Box 3)
  - Ferraro, Mary (Box 3)
  - Field, Edward (Box 3)
  - Finch, Annie (Box 3)
  - Fink, Robert Adon (Box 3)
  - Firebaugh, Henry. "Rhyme of the Fall of Berlin", See Benitez, Armando
  - Flanders, Jane (Box 3)
  - Fleshler, Daniel
    - "Holes in the Roster", ms. (Box 3)
  - Fletcher, David
    - "Expect a Miracle", ms. (Box 3)
    - Untitled novel (excerpts), ms. (Box 3)
  - Floyd, Carlisle (Box 3)
  - Flynn, Robert (Box 3)
  - Foerster, Richard
    - "Cutting Losses", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Elegy", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Patterns of Descent", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Ringing the Changes", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Toward Amber", ms. (Box 3)
  - Ford, Richard (Box 3)
  - Foreman, Laura
    - Poems, ms. (Box 3)
  - Francis, Robert
    - "Like Ghosts of Eagles", ms. (Box 3)
  - Poems, ms. (Box 3)
  - Fraser, Gregory A.
    - "Ars Poetica", ms. (Box 3)
    - "Terata", ms. (Box 3)
    - dissertation draft on William Wordsworth (Box 3)
  - French, Warren (Box 3)
  - Freund, Gerald, See [Mrs. Giles] Whiting Foundation
  - Fried, Philip
    - "Scientist of the Strange: Peter Redgrove", ms. (Box 3A)
  - Frisbie, Amy Jones (Box 3A)
  - Fulton, Alice (Box 3A)
  - Gaitskill, Mary (Box 3A)
  - Gallagher, Tess (Box 3A)
  - Gallaher, Edwin (Box 3A)
  - Gardner, Isabella (Box 3A)
  - Gates, Mary Ellen (Box 3A)
  - Gerberick, Marlene (Box 3A)
  - Gibbons, Reginald (Box 3A)
  - Gioia, Dana
    - "The Difficult Case of Howard Moss, ms. (Box 3A)
    - "Journeys in Sunlight", ms. (Box 3A)
    - "The Man in the Open Doorway", ms. (Box 3A)
    - "A Public Hearing for a Private Signal", ms. (Box 3A)
    - "Studying with Miss Bishop", ms. (Box 3A)
    - Poems (ms.) (Box 3A)
  - Gioseffi, Daniela (Box 3A)
  - Giroux, Robert, See Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc.
  - Giuliano, Edward (Box 3A)
  - Givner, Joan (Box 3A)
  - Gluck, Louise (Box 3A)
  - [David R.] Godine (Box 3A)
  - Goedicke, Patricia
    - "Invisible Horses", ms. (Box 3A)
    - "The Trail That Turns on Itself", ms. (Box 3A)
    - Poems, ms. (Box 3A)
  - Goff, Eleanor
    - "Remembrances of Delmore", ms. (Box 3A)
  - Goldbarth, Albert (Box 3A)
  - The Golden Quill Press (Box 3A)
  - Gordon, Giles (Box 3A)
  - Gordon, Jan. B. (Box 3A)
  - Gottron, Robert (Box 3A)
  - Gould, Glenn (Box 3A)
  - Goyen, William
    - "Another Man's Son", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Arcadio", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Autobiography in Fiction", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "The Collected Stories of William Goyen" (fragment), ms. (Box 3B)
    - "The Coming of Firedevil Prescott" from 'Another Man's Son'", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "The Fallen Aerialist: Marvello's Story", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Had I a Hundred Mouths", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Half a Look of Cain", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "In the Icebound Hothouse", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Leander"- ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Precious Door", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Simon's Castle", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "While You Were Away", ms. (Box 3B)
    - "Wonderful Plant", ms.; See also Writings: Interviews; Writings: Miscellaneous: Tapes (Box 29) (Box 3B)
  - Grau, Shirley Ann (Box 3B)
  - Green, George (Box 3B)
  - Green, Roger Lancelyn (Box 3B)
  - Greene, Merril
    - "The Camelot", ms. screenplay (Box 3B)
  - Gregor, Arthur (Box 3B)
  - Gregory, Blanche (Box 3B)
  - Gregory, Horace
    - "Another Look", production records (Box 3B)
    - "Spirit of Time and Place", production records (Box 3B)
  - Gregory, Patrick (Box 3B)
  - Grennan, Eamon (Box 4)
  - Grosholz, Emily (Box 4)
  - Gubernat, Susan (Box 4)
  - Guiton, Jacques E.
    - "A Life in Three Lands", ms. (Box 4)
  - Guiton, Margaret
    - "What is Diagonalism?", ms. (Box 4)
  - Gulf Coast Association of Creative Writing Teachers (GCACWT) (Box 4)
  - Gurganus, Allan (Box 4)
  - Gwynn, R. S. (Box 4)
  - H. D. (Hilda Doolittle)
    - "Aegina", ms. (Box 4)
  - Hacker, Marilyn (Box 4)
  - Hadas, Rachel (Box 4)
  - Hahn, Stephen (Box 4)
  - Haines, John (Box 4)
  - Haislip, John (Box 4)
  - Hall, Donald (Box 4)
  - [G. K.] Hall & Co. (Box 4)
  - Halpern, Daniel (Box 4)
  - Handley, Helen (Box 4)
  - Hardwick, Elizabeth (Box 4)
  - Harnack, Curtis (Box 4)
  - Harper, Michael S. (Box 4)
  - Harper Collins Publishers (Box 4)
  - Harr, Barbara J. (Box 4)
  - Hartley, Margaret L. (Box 4)
  - Haven, Stephen Harcourt
    - "Goschen", ms. (Box 4)
    - "Homework in the Rectory", ms. (Box 4)
    - "The Misty School and After: Five Contemporary Chinese Poets", ms. (Box 4)
    - "Post-Christian Poetics: Five American Poets", prospectus for dissertation (Box 4)
    - "Temple of Heaven", ms. (Box 4)
    - "Wonders of the Heart", ms. (Box 4)
  - Hazzard, Shirley (Box 4)
  - Heany, Seamus (Box 4)
  - Hecht, Anthony (Box 4)
  - Hecht, Roger (Box 4)
  - Hedren, Tippi (Box 4)
  - Hemschemeyer, Judith
    - "The Ride Home", ms. (Box 4)
  - Henderson, Bill (Box 4)
  - Herlihy, James Leo (Box 4)
  - Heyen, William
    - Correspondence, 1968-1997 (Box 4A)
    - "Aspiraling", ms. (Box 4A)
    - "The Chestnut Rain", ms. (Box 4A)
    - "The Exact Location of the Soul", ms. (Box 4A)
    - "Noise in the Trees: Poems and a Memoir", ms. (Box 4A)
    - "Noise in the Trees: Poems of Long Island", ms. (Box 4A)
    - "The Swastika Poems", ms. (Box 4A)
  - Hicks, Granville (Box 4A)
  - Hill, Billy Bob (Box 4A)
  - Hilles, Rick (Box 4A)
  - Hirsch, Edward
    - "Earthly Measures", ms. (Box 4A)
  - Hivnor, Robert Hanks (Box 4A)
  - Hochstein, Peter (Box 4A)
  - Hoffman, Arthur (Box 4A)
  - Hoffman, Daniel (Box 4A)
  - Hoggard, James
    - "Blue Paints", ms. (Box 4A)
  - Holland, Tom
    - "Concert Line", ms. (Box 4A)
  - Hollander, John (Box 4A)
  - Hollinghurst, Alan (Box 4A)
  - Holmes, Roger W. (Box 4A)
  - Holt, Robert C.
    - "American Pie", ms. (Box 5)
  - Honig, Edwin
    - "Over Time", ms. (Box 5)
  - Hopkins, Lilian B. (Box 5)
  - Horgan, Paul (Box 5)
  - Hornack, Ian (Box 5)
  - Horton, Philip (Box 5)
  - House, Rob (Box 5)
  - Houston Chronicle (Box 5)
  - Howard, Richard
    - Poems, ms. (Box 5)
    - "The Age of Anxiety" / W. H. Auden (directed by R. Howard) (Box 5)
  - Howe, Irving (Box 5)
  - Howes, Barbara
    - "Collected Poems 1945-1990", ms. (Box 5)
    - Interview, ms. (Box 5)
    - Poems, ms. (Box 5)
  - Hoyle, Arthur (Box 5)
  - Hudder, Cliff (Box 5)
  - Hudson, Derek (Box 5)
  - The Hudson Review (Box 5)
  - Huggins, Peter
    - "Blue Angels", ms. (Box 5)
  - Hughes, Olwyn (Box 5)
  - Huntington, Cynthia
    - "A Foot on the Earth", ms. (Box 5)
  - The Huntington (Box 5)
  - Hyde, Louis (Box 5)
  - Hyman, Stanley Edgar (Box 5)
  - Ignatow, David (Box 5)
  - Inez, Colette (Box 5)
  - Inprint, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Irion, Mary Jean (Box 5)
  - Irwin, John T. (Box 5)
  - Jackson, Shirley (Box 5)
  - Jacobsen, Josephine (Box 5)
  - James, Stewart
    - "Disturbances", ms. (Box 5)
  - Janos, John J. J. (Box 5)
  - Janssen, Marian (Box 5)
  - Jarrell, Mary (Mrs. Randall) (Box 5)
  - Jeffreys, M. E.
    - "The Lock-Step Limp", ms. (Box 6)
    - Poems, ms. (Box 6)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Greg (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Harold Leland (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Kate Knapp (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Rob (Box 6)
  - Jones, Gloria (Mrs. James) (Box 6)
  - Jong, Erica
    All Jong material is restricted.
    - Correspondence, 1971-1982; 2 folders (Box 0)
    - "Dearest Man-in-the-Moon", ms. (Box 0)
    - "Fear of Flying", ms. (Box 0)
    - "Half Lives", page proofs (Box 0)
    - "The Long Tunnel of Wanting You", ms. (Box 0)
    - "Loveroot", page proofs (Box 0)
    - "Success: The Great American Institution", ms. (Box 0)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 0)
    - Printed material, misc. (Box 0)
  - Junkins, Donald (Box 6)
  - Jurist, Janet (Box 6)
  - Justice, Donald Rodney (Box 6)
  - Kane, Katherine
    - "The Clock and the Cradle", ms. (Box 6)
  - Katonah Village Library (Box 6)
  - Kazin, Alfred (Box 6)
  - Kean, Ellen S. (Box 6)
  - Keating, Kenneth B. (Box 6)
  - Kelly, Richard (Box 6)
  - Kennedy, Joseph Charles, See Kennedy, X. J.
  - Kennedy, X. J. (Box 6)
  - Kermode, Frank (Box 6)
  - Kilroy, James (Box 6)
  - Kingsbury, Pam (Box 6)
  - Kinnell, Galway (Box 6)
  - Kirn, Walter (Box 6)
  - Kizer, Carolyn
    - "Yin", page proofs (Box 6)
  - Kline, Peter, See Schwartz, Delmore: "In Dreams Begin Responsibilities"
  - Kooser, Ted (Box 6)
  - Korvin, Andre de.
    - "The Day Clocks Spoke Russian", ms. (Box 6)
    - Poems, ms. (Box 6)
  - Kramer, Hilton, See The New Criterion
  - Kramer, Victor A. (Box 6)
  - Krapf, Norbert (Box 6)
  - Kumin, Maxine (Box 6)
  - Kunitz, Stanley (Box 6)
  - Kuzma, Greg (Box 6)
  - Lander, Paul (Box 6)
  - Landon, Michael (Box 6)
  - Langland, Joseph (Box 6)
  - Lanham, Fritz, See Houston Chronicle
  - Lanning, George (Box 6)
  - Larkin, Philip, See also Writings: Interviews (Box 6)
  - Lathbury, Roger, See Orchises Press
  - Laughlin, James, See New Directions; See also Writings: Interviews; Writings: Miscellaneous: Tapes (Box 29)
  - Lawner, Lynne
    - "Self-Portrait as Landscape", ms. (Box 6)
  - Lea, Sydney, See also New England Review (Box 6)
  - Lehman, David (Box 6)
  - Lehmann, John (Box 6)
  - Lehmann-Haupt, Christopher (Box 6)
  - Leibowitz, Herbert (Box 6)
  - Leising, Jared
    - "A Catechism", ms.; 2 versions in 2 folders (Box 6)
    - "In the Hole", ms.; 2 versions in 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Lennon, Florence Becker (Box 6)
  - Lenz, Siegfried (Box 6)
  - Leonard, John (Box 6)
  - Leslie, Shane (Mrs.) (Box 6)
  - Levenberg, Diane
    - "Out of the Desert", page proofs (Box 6)
  - Leverich, Lyle (Box 6)
  - Levertov, Denise (Box 6)
  - Levin, Harry (Box 6)
  - Levin, Phillis
    - "The Afterimage" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 6)
  - Levine, Anne-Marie
    - "Bus Line to a Blue Movie", ms. (Box 6)
  - The Library of Congress (Box 6)
  - Lieberman, Laurence (Box 6)
  - Lieberman, Michael (Box 6)
  - Lifshin, Lyn (Box 6)
  - Lindsay, John V. (Box 6)
  - Linney, Romulus
    - "Klonsky and Schwartz", ms. (Box 6)
  - Lipsitz, Lou
    - "The Forest in the Palm of My Hands Is Burning", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Lish, Gordon
    - "First Appearance of the Prodigal Son", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Little, Geraldine C.
    - "Molded Out of Faults", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Liu, Timothy
    - "Vox Angelica", page proofs (Box 6A)
  - Logan, John
    - "Manhattan Movements", mss. (Box 6A)
    - "Uncollected Poems", mss. (Box 6A)
  - Logan, William (Box 6A)
  - Long, Robert Emmet (Box 6A)
  - Louisiana State University Press (Box 6A)
  - Luhn, David
    - "The Judith Poems", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Lunday, Robert